Ana Valdivia

Hawthorne, CA 90250

Phone: 323-523-7129 | Email: ana.valdivia112@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ana-valdivia-69ab8b106/ | https://github.com/anabee | http://www.anavaldivia.com/

SUMMARY

Front End Web Developer with a background in Mathematics and experience in Employment Tax and project management working towards a role dedicated to user interface optimization. Certificate from the UCLA Extension Program. Experienced in extracting and transforming data and transferring it from one storage system to another. Fast learner bringing curiosity and dedication to every project. Eager for new opportunities in a challenging and collaborative environment where I can grow personally and as a team. Fluent in English and Spanish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, React, MySQL

Frontend: React.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, AJAX, REST

Backend: MongoDB, MySQL, Node.js, Express, APIs, JSON **Skills:** Github, command line, computer science fundamentals

PROJECTS

Codify | Github: https://github.com/yankidank/Codify Deployed: https://codify-jobs.herokuapp.com/

- Codify is a PWA created to organize and analyze the job application process for software developers. It provides a centralized location to save job post URLs, contact information, job offers, application status, and much more.
- Codify was built using a MERN Stack, with MongoDB and Mongoose (ODM) for our database, Express for serving, React and Materialize CSS for our frontend, and Node as our JS engine.
- Defined the React component structure and flow of the state. Created a bridge between the backend and front end using our API calls and updated the state throughout the application using React hooks, which included useEffect and set State.

WeTrivia | **Github**: https://github.com/nickrayj45/WeTrivia

Deployed: https://intense-earth-41726.herokuapp.com/

- WeTrivia is a fun, fast-paced trivia competition for you and your friends to test your knowledge in a
 variety of interesting subjects. Challenge other players to beat your high score, and share your
 experiences using an innovative chat feature as you play.
- WeTrivia was built using MySQL as the database, Express for serving, and Node as the JS engine. The
 front end was designed and made mobile responsive using Bulma and Socket.io for the chat
 functionality.
- Created and implemented the AJAX call that retrieved data from the trivia API. Created all of the logic for the trivia game, parsing and randomizing the data to get an interactive game. Created the animation of the category buttons as well as the in-game buttons.

Local Eats| Github: https://github.com/elliotfouts/local-eats

Deployed: https://elliotfouts.github.io/local-eats/

- Application assists in finding new restaurants, you can use Local Eats to find everything you need to know about the restaurant including the caliber, average cost for two, phone number, and more. You can also find suggested nearby restaurants.
- Local Eats is a simple serverless app that uses AJAX calls to retrieve data. The front end uses Skeleton to be responsive.
- Wrote the logic required to allow the user to filter their search results. Helped with making the API based AJAX call and traversing the data.

EXPERIENCE

Unemployment Tax Manager Emptech

2016 – Present

Torrance, CA

Manage daily operations of a team that delivers unemployment tax rate information to over 50 clients with multiple accounts Calculate and update information regarding state unemployment tax rates. Developed and maintained an unemployment tax rate calculating platform directly with the Web Development team which reduced production time by 75%.

Key Accomplishments:

 Worked directly with a Senior Developer to migrate historic data into an online platform that helps maintain the integrity of the functionality of the tax rate calculation process.

Front End Developer

2020 - Present

Washington Conviction Vacation Project

Github: https://github.com/openseattle/convictionvacation

This open source project helps reduce barriers faced by formerly incarcerated individuals by streamlining the process of vacating eligible convictions in Washington state. Will be assisting in ensuring that the calculations needed for the project are accurate.

Bookkeeper

2009 – 2018

Vons

Redondo Beach, CA

Handled daily incoming and outgoing monetary transactions. Delivered exceptional customer service and ensured all policies regarding transactions were followed.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js and ReactJS.

Bachelors of Arts, Geography: University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA

Associates of Science, Mathematics: El Camino College , Torrance, CA